Hello everyone.
Welcome back to our IELTS writing 5.0 to 6.0 course.
In the previous lessons, we learned about two types of questions, agree or disagree, and advantages and disadvantages.
Today we're going to find out the third question type in IELTS writing task 2, called discussion.
So, what are we waiting for?
Let's get started.
Before writing, we need to do three steps, task analysis, brainstorming, and outline.
Step one, task analysis.
In task analysis, what are the three components that we need to find in the question?
That's right.
We have to find topic words, microtopic words, and instruction words.
Now, let's do the following exercise.
Have you finished?
In this question, the three components are topic word, crime, microtopic words, result, poverty, bad person's nature.
Instruction words, discuss both views and give your opinion.
Now we've understood the main topic and the two views we'll discuss in the essay, as well as what we need to do.
Let's move on to step two, brainstorming.
I'm sure you're familiar with the six W's technique for brainstorming ideas.
Can you list what the six W's include?
Three seconds for you.
Exactly.
The six W's are the six question words including what, who, why, how, when, and where.
When brainstorming ideas, you can use these words to ask some questions related to the two views of the topic.
When you write down the ideas, you should think about whether those ideas can be used in the essay.
If any idea is not useful, you don't need to write it down to save time.
Now let's brainstorm some ideas to discuss the two views of crime.
Please fill your ideas in this table.
If any cell is not needed, we can leave it blank.
And here are some ideas that I have after applying the six W's technique.
For crime, is the result of poverty.
Why they need things they can't buy or are not educated about morality.
How they steal to eat or live and do wrong things for money.
For bad person's nature.
What they want too much, get easily angry and think negative things.
Why they are born with or learn bad ways and sometimes copy bad behaviour from others.
How they commit fraud, bully people just because they feel like it or steal like their parents.
After understanding the topic and having some ideas, let's analyse a sample essay in the next part.
Now let's take a look at the outline of this sample.
Now, let's move on to part 3 to explore the two criteria
of task response and coherence and cohesion and how to improve this sample to achieve a band 6.
First, let's evaluate this sample.
Let's evaluate the task response first.
I have the following checklist.
You can also find it in the attached PDF below.
Please pause the video for 3 minutes to evaluate the essay based on task response.
Alright, here's my answer.
This essay doesn't meet 4 requirements.
They are.
Number 2, about length because it only has 186 words.
Number 3, about thesis statement.
Number 6, about the number of explanations and examples.
As well as number 7, about conclusion.
We will analyse them in more detail and provide solutions in the sample improvements part.
Please pause the video for 2 minutes to evaluate the essay based on the following checklist.
Alright, here's my answer.
We can see that this essay has met all of these criteria
except for number 4 because the structure of paragraph 1 is not
clear and paragraph 2 is still lacking example or elaboration for the second explanation.
Next, let's pause the video for a minute to evaluate the essay based on the cohesion criterion.
Okay, here's my answer.
Basically, we can see that this essay already met the criterion of cohesion.
However, since we have not ticked all the checklists for task response
and coherence and cohesion yet, this essay is only at 5.0.
Now let's analyse and improve the sample.
We identified that the essay was too short and lacked clear examples.
Here is the improved version of the essay using the ideas we brainstormed earlier.
Notice how we added a second explanation here and used linking words here.
This raises the score to a band 6.
In this lesson, we have learned about discussion questions and understand how
to analyse discussion questions, apply the 6Ws technique to brainstorm ideas
for discussion questions, understand how to write a discussion essay at band
6.0 in task response and coherence and cohesion.
Remember to use the same structure for both body paragraphs.
Also, remember the steps to improve cohesion within the paragraph.
For now, goodbye and see you in the next lesson.
See ya!